Guide to the William H. Johnson Papers
William H. Johnson Papers
- Research Notebooks, 1956-1983; 0 linear feet
  - Experiment: Bulk Curing of Cut Tobacco Strips, BAE 133, 1970 (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - BAE 126 Freeze Drying Tests, 1970-1971 (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - BAE 134 Tests, 1970-1971 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - BAE 136, 1970-1971 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Methods of Tobacco Expansion, 1971 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - BAE 139, Cut-strip curing, 1971 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Threshing Study, 1971 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - BAE 131 Solute Transfer, 1970-1972 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Heat Treating, BAE 140, 1971-1972 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - BAE 143, Modular Curing, 1972-1973 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - BAE 147, Modular Curing, 1973 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Harvest Curing Study, 1973-1974 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Microscopic Data & Figures, 1974 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Conditioning, 1974 (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Close Grown Project, 1974 (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Close-grown Tobacco, BAE 150, correspondence, 1974-1975 (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Close-grown Tobacco, BAE 150, Literature, Plans, Observations, Data, Analyses, 1974-1975 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Close-grown Tobacco, Oxford, Harvest curing, 1974-1975 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Oxford, BAE 156 & 157, 1976 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Cyclical Curing, 1976 (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Curing Data, 1976 (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - BAE 162, Oxford Close-grown Tobacco, "Cultural" & "Harvest,", 1977 (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - BAE 162, Oxford Close-grown Tobacco, 1977 (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Oxford, 1977 (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Polyphenol Content - Freeze-drying study, 1969-1978 (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Polyphenol Content - Freeze-drying studies, BAE 126, 1969-1971 (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Solar Barn, 1978, Oxford, 1979, 1978-1979 (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Close-Grown Tobacco, Oxford, 1978-1979 (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Close-Grown Tobacco, Oxford, 79-12, 1979 (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Measured drawings of tobacco-drying apparatuses. Contains four 8.5" x 11" blue line drawings, 1970 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Measured drawings of tobacco-drying apparatuses. Contains four 22" x 33.5" drawings, 1970 (Folder 1)
  - Load Cell Oxford, 1979-1980 (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Oxford CBT, BAE 80-12, 1980 (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Nozzle Data, 1981 (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Vertical Seeder Lab Test, 1981 (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - BAE 81-20, 1981 (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Small Barns, Oxford, 81-13, 1981-1982 (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Raleigh BAE 82-20, 1982 (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - Oxford BAE 82-30, 1982 (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - BAE 83-20, Raleigh, 1983 (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Oxford, BAE 83-11A, 1983 (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - BAE 83-30, 1983 (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Solar Curing Notes, 1978 (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Solar Barn, 1980 (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Oxford Solar Barn, 82-11, 1981-1982 (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Heat Exchange Data, Solar Curing, 1982 (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - Untitled Binder: Diagrams, Notes, & Data, 1981-1982 (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - Resource Requests & Experimental Plans, 1962-1983 (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Close-Grown Tobacco, BAE 150, "Effect of Tobacco Seed Placement at Various Depths on Germination Under Greenhouse Conditions,", 1975 (Box 46, Folder 1)
- Departmental, University, and Other Professional Papers, 1954-2005; 0 linear feet
  The William H. Johnson Departmental, University, and Other Professional Papers series is made up of papers associated with Johnson's tenure at North Carolina State University, including committee information, personnel forms, and university correspondence.
  - ASAE Materials, 2001-2005 (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - ASAE Materials, 1990-1997 (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - ASAE Materials, 1984-1989 (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - ASAE Style Manual, 1991-1993 and undated (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - State ASAE Materials, 1983-1995 and undated (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - College, 1994-2002 (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - Alpha Epsilon, 1970 (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - Gamma Sigma Delta, 1972 (Box 23, Folder 9)
  - Committees, 2002-2004 (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Bond Scholarship Committee, 1996 (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - Biological & Agricultural Engineering PR & Development, 1998 (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - PR & Development Committee, 1997-1998 (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - Advisory Committee, 1998 (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - Campaign Endowment & Capital Funds, 1998 (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - Church - UMC, 1999 (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - Reports, PR2B University Personnel Report, 1997-2003 (Box 24, Folder 8)
  - CVs & Personal Info, 1956-1996 (Box 24, Folder 9)
  - Personal - WH Johnson, 1983-1996 (Box 24, Folder 10)
  - Interview & Application info, 1983 (Box 24, Folder 11)
  - PR2B, 1993-1994 (Box 24, Folder 12)
  - PR2B, 1991-1992 (Box 24, Folder 13)
  - PR2B, 1990-1991 (Box 24, Folder 14)
  - CV - WHJ, 1952-1994 (Box 24, Folder 15)
  - "An Expanded Program In Bioengineering At North Carolina State of UNC,", 1964 (Box 24, Folder 16)
  - Departmental Papers, 1993-1995 (Box 24, Folder 17)
  - Departmental General Correspondence, 1961-2003 (Box 24, Folder 18)
  - CSRS Review, 1996 and undated (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Meetings, 1994-2003 (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - David Beasley, 1994-2000 (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Experiment Station - General, 1997-2000 (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - University memoranda on effort reporting and other official business, 1996-2002 (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Other Universities (correspondence), 1965-1982 (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - William H. Johnson - Academic Record, 1952-1961 (Box 46, Folder 22)
  - MC0006235D003, 3.5" floppy disk containing CV and publication list for William H. Johnson, 2000 (Cardbox 47)
- Papers, Publications, and Presentations, 1958-2004; 1958 2004; 4.75 linear feet
  William H. Johnson wrote and published over seventy papers and gave numerous presentations at tobacco, agriculture, and engineering conferences around the country and across the world. The Papers, Publications, and Presentations series contains copies of Johnson's many articles and other publications, as well as notes on many of his presentations.
  - Article reprints, 1958-1969 (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - Article reprints, 1970-1979 (Box 25, Folder 8)
  - Article reprints, 1980-2003 (Box 25, Folder 9)
  - Abstracts, 2001-2002 (Box 25, Folder 10)
  - Presentation: Tobacco Workers' Conference 2004, "Computer-Controlled Energy Management in Tobacco Curing Systems," (Box 25, Folder 11)
  - Presentation: Tobacco Workers' Conference 2002, "Energy/Dry-Bulb Control System for Tobacco Curing," (Box 25, Folder 12)
  - Presentation: Tobacco Workers' Conference 2002, "Observations on Wet-bulb Sensing in Tobacco Curing," (Box 25, Folder 13)
  - Presentation: Tobacco Workers' Conference 2000, "Temperature Differential (TD) Control of Drying Rate in Tobacco Curing," (Box 25, Folder 14)
  - Manuscript Reviews, 1996-2003 (Box 25, Folder 15)
  - Paper: "Pressure vs. Airflow Characteristics Through Fresh Intact and Cut-Strip Tobacco,", 1998 (Box 25, Folder 16)
  - Paper: "Damper Control Algorithms,", 1999 (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Paper: "Modeling Moisture and Chemical Changes During Bulk Curing of Flue-Cured Tobacco,", 2000-2005 (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - Tobacco International, 1998 (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - News articles, 1996 (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - Patent info - Reducing Nitrosamines (Curing), 2001 (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - Energy & Bulk Barn Seminar: "Energy Saving Potentials in Tobacco Curing,", 1977-1978 (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - Energy Requirements in Tobacco Curing, NC State ASAE, Talks - Energy Reduction, 1975-1980 (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - Paper: Simulation of Packing Density Distribution - Chang & Johnson, 1975-1977 (Box 26, Folder 8)
  - World Tobacco Symposium, London, 1975: "Keys to Tobacco Farm Productivity," (Box 26, Folder 9)
  - CORESTA/TCRC Paper, 1971-1973 (Box 26, Folder 10)
  - Slide Arrangements for Talks, undated (Box 26, Folder 11)
  - Paper: "Specific Volume vs. Specific Surface Area," Chang & Johnson, 1972-1973 (Box 26, Folder 12)
  - Paper: "Microscopic Studies of Bright Leaf Tobacco,", 1971 (Box 26, Folder 13)
  - Paper: "Weight & Moisture Distribution in Uncured Tobacco,", 1975-1980 (Box 26, Folder 14)
  - ASAE Paper: "Solar Energy & Heat Recycling," slides, winter 1979 (Box 26, Folder 15)
  - "Solar Energy & Heat Recycling," review requests & notes, 1946-1980 (Box 26, Folder 16)
  - "Solar Energy & Heat Recycling in Tobacco Curing," manuscript, 1979-1981 (Box 26, Folder 17)
  - Presentation, ASAE, Kentucky: "Modular Tobacco Handling & Curing System,", 1973-1975 (Box 26, Folder 18)
  - World Tobacco Symposium, Geneva, 1972 (Box 26, Folder 19)
  - World Tobacco Symposium, London, 1975 (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - CORESTA - Montreux, 1974 (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - Presentation: "New Potentials in Tobacco Mechanization," Canada trip, 1975 (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - Trip to Canada, 7/22/75, 1975 (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - "for 2x2 slides,", undated (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - Paper, Tobacco Chemists' Conference: "Production Factors Affecting Chemical Properties of the Flue-Cured Leaf: Curing,", 1974 (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - Draft of paper - CORESTA, Manila, 1980 and undated (Box 27, Folder 7)
  - Slides, undated (Box 27, Folder 8)
  - World Tobacco Symposium, Geneva, Presentation notes, 1972 (Box 27, Folder 9)
  - World Tobacco Symposium, Geneva, itinerary and related materials, 1972 (Box 27, Folder 10)
  - Paper: "Developmental Physiology of the Tobacco Seedling,", 1978 (Box 27, Folder 11)
  - Paper: "Heat Loss Through Concrete Floors - Bulk Barn" - Chang, Blum, & Johnson, 1978-1979 (Box 27, Folder 12)
  - Paper: "A Bulk Curing Facility for Experimental Flue-Cured Tobacco" - Ray Campbell, 1979-1981 (Box 27, Folder 13)
  - Extended Curing, 1964-1965 (Box 27, Folder 14)
  - Paper: "Scanning Electron Microscope: Application to the Study of Plant Anatomy,", 1971 (Box 27, Folder 15)
  - Paper: "Freeze-Drying of Tobacco," with 56 black & white photos, 1970 (Box 27, Folder 16)
  - Paper: "Effects of Freeze-Drying on TDE, DDT, & Endosulfan in Tobacco,", undated (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - Paper: "Scanning Electron Microscopic Structure of Chloroplasts and Other Subcellular Bodies of Tobacco Leaf Tissue,", 1973-1974 (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - Paper: "Studies on the Heat Transfer Properties of Tobacco During Freeze-Drying,", 1973-1974 (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - Paper: "A Method & Apparatus for Rapid Turgor Conditioning Prior to Freeze-Drying,", undated (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - Paper, Montreux, Switzerland, CORESTA meeting: "Recent Progress in the Modular Handling & Curing of Tobacco,", 1974 (Box 28, Folder 5)
  - Paper: "Effects of Metabolic Inhibitors," Arcila, Mohapatra, & Johnson, 1982 (Box 28, Folder 6)
  - "Phytotron Studies in Tobacco Seedling Production," manuscript, 1982 (Box 28, Folder 7)
  - Paper: "Microscopic Studies of Bright Leaf Tobacco, III,", 1973 (Box 28, Folder 8)
  - Paper: "Scanning Electron Microscopic Observations on Crystals in Tobacco Leaf Tissue,", 1974 (Box 28, Folder 9)
  - Paper: "Developments & Prospects in the Bulk Curing of Virginia-Type Tobacco,", 1963 and undated (Box 28, Folder 10)
  - Paper: "Carbon Dioxide Liberation & Carbohydrate Accumulation During the Yellowing Phase of Tobacco Curing,", 1963 (Box 28, Folder 11)
  - Paper: "Effect of Temperature & Moisture on the Inactivation of O-Diphenol Oxidase,", undated (Box 28, Folder 12)
  - Paper: "Influence of Harvesting and Process Variables on Bulk Curing of Bright Leaf Tobacco,", 1965 (Box 28, Folder 13)
  - Paper: "Oxygen Depletion by Respiration for Bright Leaf Tobacco in a Closed Curing System,", 1965-1966 (Box 28, Folder 14)
  - Paper: "Changes in the Free Amino Acids of Tobacco During Curing," Proceedings of the 4th International Tobacco Science Congress, Athens, Greece, 1966 (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - Paper: "An Instrument for Determining Spectrofluorometric Properties of Biological Materials,", undated, possibly 1966 (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - Paper: "Corrected Fluorescence Excitation and Emission Spectra of Bright Leaf Tobacco,", undated, possibly 1966 (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - Paper: "New Processing Methods in the Premanufacturing of Tobacco," Hamburg, 1970-1981 (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - Old publications on conventional curing of flue-cured tobacco, 1943-1987 (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - Microscopic studies of flue-cured & freeze-dried Tobacco, 1971-1972 (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - Characterization of oxidative browning in flue-cured tobacco: I. A Method for evaluating varietal discoloration potentials, 1969 (Box 32, Folder 2)
  - Thermal analysis of oxidative browning in flue-cured tobacco, undated (Box 32, Folder 3)
  - Post-curing conditioning of tobacco in bulk systems, 1969 (Box 32, Folder 4)
  - Temperature differential as a control parameter in tobacco curing, 1968 (Box 32, Folder 5)
  - Kinetics of moisture movement in hygroscopic materials. II. An Application to foliar materials, 1968 (Box 32, Folder 6)
  - Kinetics of moisture movement in hygroscopic materials. I. Theoretical considerations of drying phenomena, 1967-1968 (Box 32, Folder 7)
  - Influence of harvesting procedures & curing variables on characteristics of Virginia-type tobacco, 1966 (Box 32, Folder 8)
  - Physical & biological relations in the rapid drying of foliar materials, 1967 (Box 32, Folder 9)
  - Changes in selected chemical constituents due to sudden thermal treatments during curing of flue-cured tobacco, 1970 (Box 32, Folder 10)
  - Bulk thermal conductivity of cured bright tobacco shreds during freeze-drying, 1971-1973 (Box 32, Folder 11)
  - Phytotron studies on tobacco seedling production. I. Effect of plant spacing on growth, 1979 (Box 32, Folder 12)
  - High temperature convective drying of tobacco during curing: I. Effect of air temperature and velocity on leaf temperature & drying rate, undated (Box 32, Folder 13)
  - Transport phenomena in high temperature convective drying of foliar material, 1969 (Box 33, Folder 1)
  - High temperature convective drying of tobacco during curing: II. Effect of air temperature and velocity on heat and mass transfer coefficients, 1971 (Box 33, Folder 2)
  - Summary paper: "Curing & Fermentation,", undated (Box 33, Folder 3)
  - High temperature discoloration phenomena of foliar materials, 1970-1972 (Box 33, Folder 4)
  - Tobacco chemistry 8: Chemical & cilotoxic studies of smoke from heat-treated tobacco, 1970-1972 (Box 33, Folder 5)
  - New processing methods in the premanufacturing of tobacco, 1970-1972 (Box 33, Folder 6)
  - Indirect dissolved oxygen polarography of whole seed respiration, Mohapatra & Johnson, 1978-1983 (Box 33, Folder 7)
  - Comparative biochemical changes during the yellowing & drying phases of tobacco curing, 1979 (Box 33, Folder 8)
  - ASAE paper: Development of a cross-flow modular curing system, 1976-1977 (Box 33, Folder 9)
  - Thermal conductivity of cured tobacco shreds in moist, frozen, & freeze-dried states, 1979 (Box 33, Folder 10)
  - Rapid drying of yellowed flue-cured tobacco - "Experimental,", 1963-1995 (Box 33, Folder 11)
  - Rapid drying of yellowed flue-cured tobacco - manuscripts and photos, 1995-1997 (Box 34, Folder 1)
  - Handling and curing characteristics of cut-strip tobacco. Part I: Effect of strip size, packing density, and mode of orientation. Manuscript submitted to Tobacco Science, 1996-2002 (Box 34, Folder 2)
  - Handling and curing characteristics of cut-strip tobacco. Part I: Effect of strip size, packing density, and mode of orientation. Manuscript submitted to Beitrage zur Tabakforschung International, 2001-2002 (Box 34, Folder 3)
  - Handling and curing characteristics of cut-strip tobacco. Part I: Effect of strip size, packing density, and mode of orientation. Clayton data., 1996 (Box 34, Folder 4)
  - Handling and curing characteristics of cut-strip tobacco. Part I: Effect of strip size, packing density, and mode of orientation. Analyses., 1996 (Box 34, Folder 5)
  - Handling and curing characteristics of cut-strip tobacco. Part I: Effect of strip size, packing density, and mode of orientation. Other materials., 2000 and undated (Box 34, Folder 6)
  - Handling and curing characteristics of cut-strip tobacco. Part II: Effect of yellowing time and drying potential. Reprints., 2002 (Box 34, Folder 7)
  - Handling and curing characteristics of cut-strip tobacco. Part II: Effect of yellowing time and drying potential. Oxford data., 1997 (Box 34, Folder 8)
  - Handling and curing characteristics of cut-strip tobacco. Part II: Effect of yellowing time and drying potential. Manuscript submitted to Beitrage zur Tabakforschung International., 2001-2002 (Box 34, Folder 9)
  - Handling and curing characteristics of cut-strip tobacco. Part II: Effect of yellowing time and drying potential. Experiment., 1997 (Box 34, Folder 10)
  - Handling and curing characteristics of cut-strip tobacco. Part II: Effect of yellowing time and drying potential. Clayton data., 1997 (Box 34, Folder 11)
  - World Tobacco Symposium program, 1972 (Box 46, Folder 2)
  - Rapid Drying of Yellow Leaf Experiment, undated (Box 46, Folder 5)
  - MC0006235D001, 3.5" floppy disk containing "Cut-strip 96 for Tob Sci" and related word documents, 1996-1999 (Cardbox 47)
  - MC0006235D002, 3.5" floppy disk containing "Cut-Strip 97 for Tob Sci" and other word documents, 1997-1998 (Cardbox 47)
- Tobacco Bulk Curing Files, 1950-1982; 1950 1982; 2 linear feet
  William H. Johnson was part of the research team that developed the tobacco bulk curing process, and the Tobacco Bulk Curing Files series contains notes, reports, and photographs documenting this research.
  - "Developments in Bulk Curing of Bright Leaf Tobacco" and "Bulk Curing Simplifies Tobacco Mechanization,", 1957-1960 (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - Bulk Curing Miscellaneous items, 1957-1960 (Box 29, Folder 7)
  - "Effects of Bruising on Tobacco Curability,", 1957 (Box 29, Folder 8)
  - "Effects of Bruising on Tobacco Curability" - data and photos, 1957 and undated (Box 29, Folder 9)
  - "Photos, shredding, etc; around 1957-1958,", 1967 1983 (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - Various photos taken during the 1950s (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - Oxford, 1956, Bulk Curing Research files and photos (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - Bulk Curing - lab cabinets, 1957 (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - Bulk Curing photos, 1958-1959 (Box 30, Folder 5)
  - Other Photos, Oxford, 1950s (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - Work on multi-barn system, 1982 and undated (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - Williamson & Johnson research notes, 1978-1980 (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - Williamson, Johnson, & Gwynn: Infrared (Heat) Experiment - BAE 82-13, samples 2301-2420; data, forms, & code, 1982-1983 (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - Williamson, Johnson, & Gwynn: Infrared (Heat) Experiment - BAE 82-13, 2301-2420 notes; Williamson & Johnson, general notes on Atmospheric Infrared (Heat) & Burley Experiment, BAE 82-20, BAE 82-13, BAE 82-30, 1982 (Box 31, Folder 5)
  - Williamson-Johnson, Atmosphere Experiment BAE 82-20, samples 2101-2199 & 2201-2209 notes, 1982 (Box 31, Folder 6)
  - Williamson-Johnson, Atmosphere Experiment BAE 82-20, data, forms, & code, samples 2101-2199 & 2201-2209, 1982 (Box 31, Folder 7)
  - Williamson-Johnson, Burley Curing Experiment, BAE 82-30 samples, notes, 1982 (Box 31, Folder 8)
  - Williamson-Johnson, Burley Curing Experiment, BAE 82-30 samples; data, forms, & code, 1982 (Box 31, Folder 9)
  - Direct Seeding/Fluid Drill, 1972-1984 (Box 31, Folder 10)
  - Psychrometrics, 1972 (Box 31, Folder 11)
  - "Other Concepts,", 2003 & undated (Box 31, Folder 12)
  - Bulk Curing Miscellaneous items, 1956-1958 (Box 46, Folder 3)
  - Williamson, Johnson, Gwynn, 1982, Infrared (Heat) Experiment, BAE 82-13, 2301-2420, notes; Williamson, Johnson, 1982, General Notes on Atmospheric Infrared (Heat) & Burley Experiment, BAE 82-20, BAE 82-13, and BAE 82-30 (Box 46, Folder 4)
- Energy Advisory Task Force Files, 1976-1983; 1976 1983; 2 linear feet
  From 1979 to 1980 William H. Johnson chaired the Energy Advisory Task Force, a joint venture of N.C. State's School of Agriculture and Life Sciences and School of Forest Resources. The Energy Advisory Task Force Files series documents Johnson's research and activities related to energy use and conservation and explorations of new energy sources.
  - Bio-energy '80, World Congress and Exposition., 1980-1982 (Box 34, Folder 12)
  - Slides - W.H. Johnson, "Energy and North Carolina Agriculture,", undated (Box 34, Folder 13)
  - Southeastern Seminary, 1983 (Box 34, Folder 14)
  - NCSU Energy Group (& microwave), 1976-1978 (Box 35, Folder 1)
  - Tobacco Energy Audit, 1981 (Box 35, Folder 2)
  - Draft statement on energy use and conservation, 1983 (Box 35, Folder 3)
  - Energy Survey - no activity, 1979 (Box 35, Folder 4)
  - Extension Energy Projects, 1977-1979 (Box 35, Folder 5)
  - Energy-Related Research & Extension Activities lists, 1979 (Box 35, Folder 6)
  - Energy Survey, 1979-1981 (Box 35, Folder 7)
  - Energy Advisory Task Force Miscellaneous Items, 1979 (Box 35, Folder 8)
  - Popularized version of "North Carolina Agriculture and Forestry: Energy Needs and Potential Contributions,", 1980 (Box 35, Folder 9)
  - Energy Use Optimization, 1981 (Box 35, Folder 10)
  - Report of Energy Advisory Task Force, 1980 (Box 35, Folder 11)
  - Notes on energy & biomass, undated (Box 35, Folder 12)
  - "Energy Advisory Task Force, 1979,", 1979-1980 (Box 35, Folder 13)
  - Survey of Energy Projects, 1979 (Box 35, Folder 14)
  - Mid-American Biomass Energy Workshop, Purdue University, 1979 (Box 36, Folder 1)
  - Energy Programs, United States, 1978-1982 (Box 36, Folder 2)
  - "World For Energy,", 1978-1979 (Box 36, Folder 3)
  - Solar Energy Information Data Bank Publications Bulletin, 1979 (Box 36, Folder 4)
  - Energy Conference, May 4-6, 1978 (Box 36, Folder 5)
  - Energy Newspaper Articles, 1979 & undated (Box 36, Folder 6)
  - Wood Burning Equipment, 1979 (Box 36, Folder 7)
  - Energy Recovery Units, 1978 & undated (Box 36, Folder 8)
  - Wood Gasification & Combustion, 1979 (Box 36, Folder 9)
  - 1979 Mid-American Biomass Energy Workshop address list (Box 46, Folder 6)
- Tobacco Committees, Consulting, Reports, and Related Files, 1962-1984; 1962 1984; 3.5 linear feet
  William H. Johnson Tobacco Committees, Consulting, Reports, and Related Files series documents Johnson's involvement in tobacco-related committees and his work as a consultant.
  - Tobacco Research Field Day Steering Committee, 1981 (Box 36, Folder 10)
  - Consulting Agreement, Research Triangle Institute, 1973-1979 (Box 36, Folder 11)
  - Committee on Packaging & Handling of Untied Flue-Cured Tobacco, 1973-1976 (Box 36, Folder 12)
  - Philip Morris Proposals, 1983 (Box 36, Folder 13)
  - NC Energy Institute Proposal, 1978 (Box 36, Folder 14)
  - Tobacco Foundation (Proposals & Reports), 1977-1984 (Box 36, Folder 15)
  - Potential Projects & Papers, undated (Box 36, Folder 16)
  - Review of Dr. Sugg's Project Outline, 1982 (Box 37, Folder 1)
  - Research Apprenticeships, 1982 (Box 37, Folder 2)
  - Post-Doctoral Position in Tobacco Research, 1983 (Box 37, Folder 3)
  - Optimization of Tobacco Curing Systems Project, 1978-1984 (Box 37, Folder 4)
  - S-147 Project Reports & Related materials, 1979-1983 (Box 37, Folder 5)
  - Research Summaries, 1981 (Box 37, Folder 6)
  - Equipment Supply Purchases, 1979-1980 (Box 37, Folder 7)
  - Oxford Research Notes, 1974-1978 (Box 37, Folder 8)
  - CORESTA - 4th International Tobacco Scientific Congress, Rapporteur, 1966 (Box 37, Folder 9)
  - WHJ Report - Research Proposal on Natural & Mechanical Drying of Paddy, 1966 (Box 37, Folder 10)
  - Report on Trip to Indian Institute of Technology, Kharagpur, India, 1966-1967 (Box 37, Folder 11)
  - Documents for trip to India with assignment at Kharagpur, 1966 (Box 37, Folder 12)
  - Project Outline - "Improved Systems for Transplant Production & Direct Seeding of Tobacco,", 1982 (Box 38, Folder 1)
  - Regional Project Outline, S-147, 1977-1980 (Box 38, Folder 2)
  - Report of Task Force Number 6: Tobacco Production and Marketing, 1972 (Box 38, Folder 3)
  - Research Review for Athens, 1955-1966 (Box 38, Folder 4)